人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译 双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：斑驳的小屋    芒果妖怪    苏也
■
校对：慕风夕
后期：L.C.  时间轴：Jessie   GY粢糕
黑暗
Darkness.
是我的初始记忆
That's the first thing I remember.
黑暗  阴冷
It was dark, and it was cold.
令我害怕
And I was scared.
那时...就在那时
But then,
我看到了月亮
then I saw the moon.
月亮又大又亮
It was so big and it was so bright.
像要将所有的黑暗驱散
It seemed to chase the darkness away.
彼时光明骤现
And when it did,
我不再害怕
I wasn't scared anymore.
我为什么在这里  我要做什么
Why I was there and what I was meant to do,
我都不知道
that I've never known.
我疑心自己永远不会知道
And a part of me wonders if I ever will.
你好  你好
Hello. Hello.
晚上好  女士  女士
Good evening, ma'am. Ma'am?
打扰一下  请问这是哪里
Excuse me. Can you tell me where I am?
有人能看到我吗
Hello?
我叫冰霜侠杰克
My name is Jack Frost.
我从何而知的呢
How do I know that?
是月亮告诉我的
The moon told me so.
但他告诉我的  也仅此而已
But that was all he ever told me.
那还是很久  很久以前的事情了
And that was a long, long time ago.
300年后  北极
淘气
我还在等着吃曲奇饼哟
Still waiting for cookies!
完成了
Yes!
终于完成了
Finally!
跟你说过多少遍了  要敲门
How many times have I told you to knock?
什么
What?
地球怎么了
The Globe?
小尖头们  让路
Shoo with your pointy heads.
你们怎么总在脚底下转悠
Why are you always under boot?
这是什么
What is this?
查过地轴了吗  地球的转动还正常吗
Have you checked the axis? Is rotation balanced?
可能是他吗
Can it be?
小铃铛们
Dingle!
做好准备
Make preparations.
有客人要来
We are going to have company.
18颗门牙
Eighteen central incisors.
莫斯科  第九区
Moscow, sector 9.
22颗门牙  18颗前臼齿
22 incisors, 18 premolars.
大雨警报
Heavy rain advisory.
得梅因[美国城市]枫树街23号犬齿一颗
Des Moines, we've got a cuspid at 23 Maple.
出发
Head out!
等等  这是她第一颗牙齿
Wait! It's her first tooth.
你这辈子见过
Have you ever seen a more adorable
这么漂亮的侧切牙吗
lateral incisor in all of your life?
看她清理的多干净啊
Look how she flossed.
众位守卫者
My fellow Guardians,
我们有责任守护全世界的孩子
it is ourjob to watch over the children of the world
确保他们的安全
and keep them safe.
给他们带去快乐  希望和梦想
To bring wonder, hope, and dreams.
今天将大家召集起来的
And so I have called us all here
唯一原因就是
for one reason, and one reason only.
孩子们有危险了
The children are in danger.
被我们赶走几百年的敌人
An enemy we have kept at bay for centuries
最终决定报复反攻了
has finally decided to strike back.
我们要阻止他
We alone can stop him.
天啊  冻死了
It's freezing!
我脚都冻麻了 没有知觉了
I can't feel my feet! I can't feel my feet!
曲奇饼  蛋酒  谁要吃
Cookies? Eggnog? Anyone?
最好是要紧事  诺斯
This better be good, North.
睡神  谢谢你能来
Sandy, thank you for coming.
我明白  我明白
I know, I know.
但如果不是事态紧急的话
But I obviously wouldn't have called you all here
我不会召集大家来的
unless it was serious.
黑暗梦魇来了 就在北极
The Boogeyman was here! At the Pole!
比奇
Pitch?
比奇·布莱克来这里了
Pitch Black? Here?
是他
Yes.
刚刚黑沙覆盖了整个地球
There was black sand covering the Globe.
什么黑沙
What do you mean, black sand?
接着一片黑影...
And then a shadow!
等下  你说你看到了比奇
Hold on, hold on. I thought you said you saw Pitch.
也不完全是
Well, not exactly.
"不完全是" 你们信他说的话吗
"Not exactly"? Can you believe this guy?
睡神  你已经做出回答了
Yeah. You said it, Sandy.
听着  他肯定密谋要做坏事
Look, he's up to something very bad.
我的肚子...
I feel it
感觉到了
in my belly.
等一下  等等
Hang on, hang on.
还差三天就复活节了  你因为肚子难受
You mean to say you summoned me here three days before Easter
就让我大老远赶来了
because of your belly?
老大
Mate,
要是圣诞前三天我也这么摆你一道
if I did this to you three days before Christmas...
拜托  复活节兔
Please, Bunny.
复活节和圣诞节根本就是两码事嘛
Easter is not Christmas.
又来了
Here we go.
诺斯  我真的没时间和你们玩
North, I don't have time for this!
我还有两百万个彩蛋要画呢
I've still got two million eggs to finish up!
不论你画多少  鸡蛋也变不成小鸡啊
No matter how much you paint, is still egg.
鸡蛋是易变质食品
Look, mate, I'm dealing with perishables.
即使如此  你有一年的准备时间啊
Right? You've got all year to prepare!
兔子怎么总是这么不淡定
Why are rabbits always so nervous?
那你怎么老是这么唠叨
And why are you always such a blowhard?
牙仙 难道你没看到我们在吵架吗
Tooth! Can't you see we're trying to argue?
不好意思
Sorry.
但我不像你们
Not all of us
那么好命  每年只工作一晚
get to work one night a year.
对吧  睡神
Am I right, Sandy?
圣地亚哥  第二区...
San Diego, sector 2.
算了吧  伙计
Come on, mate.
比奇和黑暗时代已经一去不返了
Pitch went out with the Dark Ages.
我们确定过的
We made sure of it.
但我知道  肯定是他 现在情况紧急
I know it was him. We have serious situation.
我画彩蛋难道不是情况紧急吗
Well, I've got a serious situation with some eggs.
对啊  还有月中人呢
Man in Moon!
睡神  你早怎么不说
Sandy, why didn't you say something?
好久不见  老朋友
It's been a long time, old friend.
有什么重大消息
What is big news?
确实是比奇回来了
It is Pitch.
曼尼  我们要怎么做
Manny, what must we do?
各位  这是什么意思
Guys, you know what this means?
他在挑选新的守护者
He's choosing a new Guardian.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
事态肯定很严重
Must be big deal.
曼尼认为我们需要帮助
Manny thinks we need help.
我们什么时候开始需要帮助了
Since when do we need help?
我比较好奇新的守护者是谁
I wonder who it's gonna be!
爱尔兰民间传说精灵  貌似矮小老人
会不会是小矮妖
Maybe the Leprechaun?
千万别是土拨鼠  千万别是土拨鼠
Please not the Groundhog, please not the Groundhog.
是冰霜侠杰克
Jack Frost.
我收回之前的话  还是换土拨鼠吧
I take it back. The Groundhog's fine.
只要他能帮助我们保护孩子们就行
As long as he helps to protect the children.
对吧
Right?
怎么可能  冰霜侠杰克才不在乎小孩子
Jack Frost? He doesn't care about children!
他就会把水管冻住
All right? All he does is freeze water pipes
在寻找复活节彩蛋的时候跟我捣乱
and mess with my egg hunts!
他就是个自私自利  不负责任的...
All right? He's an irresponsible, selfish...
守护者
Guardian.
说他是什么都行
Jack Frost is many things,
但绝对不是守护者
but he is not a Guardian.
真是好玩  太过瘾了
Now that, that was fun.
风儿
Wind!
带我回家吧
Take me home.
看我的表现吧
Snow day!
冻死人了
It's freezing!
神秘时代  他们就在那里
这本书看起来不错  好看吗
That looks interesting. Good book?
-太好了  -是啊
-All right! -Yeah!
-真好  下雪了 -下雪喽
-Snow day! -Snow day! Yeah.
不客气
You're welcome.
等等我
Guys, wait up!
你们周末去不去寻找复活节彩蛋吗
Are you guys coming to the egg hunt Sunday?
当然去  可以吃免费糖果
Yeah! Free candy.
多希望找彩蛋时也下雪啊
I hope we can find the eggs with all this snow!
书上说
It says here that
他们在密歇根州找到了大脚怪的
they found Bigfoot hair samples
皮毛样本和DNA
and DNA in Michigan!
真是太酷了
That's like super-close!
又来了
Here we go again.
我们也看了那段视频  克劳德
You saw the video too, Claude.
他真的存在
He's out there.
你说外星人也存在的
That's what you said about aliens.
还有复活节兔子
And the Easter Bunny!
复活节兔真的存在
The Easter Bunny is real.
是  他真的存在
He's real all right.
我们都认识这只脾气暴躁
Real annoying,
目中无人的兔子
real grumpy and really full of himself.
算了吧  你们什么都信
Come on! You guys will believe anything.
复活节兔  跳跳跳
Easter Bunny, hop, hop, hop!
妈妈  索菲又摔倒了
Mom, Sophie fell again!
没事吧  索菲
You okay, Soph?
杰米  戴好帽子
Jamie, hat.
要不冰霜侠杰克会让你冻得流鼻涕
We don't want Jack Frost nipping at your nose.
冰霜侠杰克是谁
Who's Jack Frost?
谁都不是  宝贝  这就是种说法
No one, honey. It's just an expression.
我的大名你们都没听过
"Who's Jack Frost?"
刚刚是谁扔的
Okay, who threw that?
反正不是大脚怪  小鬼
Well, it wasn't Bigfoot, kiddo.
杰米·班尼特  你干嘛扔我  不公平
Jamie Bennett, no fair!
是你先拿雪球扔我的
You struck first!
大伙儿一起来吧
Free-for-all!
谁需要更多弹药
All right, who needs ammo?
好玩吧
Look at that!
坏了  我砸到虎妞了
Crud! I hit Cupcake!
-她砸到虎妞了 -你居然砸了虎妞
-She hit Cupcake. -You hit Cupcake?
-刚那个是你扔的吗 -不是
-Did you throw that? -No.
也不是我
It wasn't me!
有点滑哦
A little slippery!
杰米  小心点  停下来
Jamie, watch out!
-滑向马路了  -快停下  车流很猛
-That's the street! -Stop! There's traffic!
杰米  有我呢  别担心
Don't worry, Jamie. I got you. Hold on!
不会有事的
It's gonna be all right!
跟着我走  左拐
Keep up with me, kid! Take a left!
慢点
Slow down!
停下  不不不
Hold up. No, no, no, no.
刚那是杰米·班尼特吗
Is that Jamie Bennett?
-滑得不错  -不  不行
-There you go. -No, no!
-天啊  -太好了
-My gosh! -Yeah!
看样子摔得不轻
That looks serious.
杰米  你还好吗
Jamie, are you all right?
你们看到了吗  真是棒极了
Did you guys see that? It was amazing!
我在冰上从那跳过去
I did a jump
然后从那下边滑...
and I slid under a...
太帅了  掉了一颗牙
Cool! A tooth!
-那就是钱啊 -牙仙给的零用钱
-Dude, that means cash! -Tooth fairy cash!
-不是吧  -你真走运
-Oh, no! -You lucky bum!
我要把它放到枕头底下
I got to put this under my pillow!
等一下  等等  别走
Wait a minute. Come on. Hold on, hold on.
难道你们都忘了刚才的快乐时光吗
What about all the fun we just had?
那可不是牙仙的功劳  是我
That wasn't the Tooth Fairy, that was me!
我的耳朵都要冻掉了
My ears are freezing!
我要怎么做才能让人注意到我
What's a guy got to do to get a little attention around here?
那一片结冰了
There was a patch of ice.
我都不知道怎么会这样
I don't understand how it got here.
复活节马上就要来了
I mean, Easter is around the corner!
...那感觉真是棒极了
...It was awesome!
我从小山丘上飞下来
So then I was flying down this hill
在滚滚车流中自如穿梭
and it was like... through these cars
后来雪橇碰到了那个东西
and then the sled hit this thing
我就飞到了空中
and it was like way up in the air!
然后嘭一声被沙发撞倒
And then, bam, the sofa hit me...
然后  我的牙就掉了
...And see, my tooth came out!
好了  别玩了  把牙放到枕头下了吗
All right, you. Tooth under your pillow?
是的  放好了
Yeah, I'm ready.
杰米  早点睡吧
Now don't stay up trying to see her, Jamie,
否则她是不会来的哦
or she won't come.
现在也能看啊 要帮我吗  索菲
But I can do it this time! You want to help me, Soph?
咱们藏起来等着看牙仙
We can hide and see the Tooth Fairy!
藏起来  藏起来
Hide, hide, hide, hide.
那可不行  赶快上床睡觉吧  小帅哥
Straight to bed now, mister.
妈妈...
Mom.
如果我做错了什么事情
If there's something I'm doing wrong,
能不能请你告诉我
can you just tell me what it is?
因为我已经试了所有的方法
Because I've tried everything
但没有一个人能看到我
and no one ever sees me.
是你把我带到这里来的
You put me here.
至少你应该告诉我...
The least you can do is tell me...
告诉我为什么
Tell me why.
来的真及时  睡神
Right on time, Sandman.
我还以为听到了独角兽的蹄声
I thought I heard the clippity-clop of a unicorn.
多么美好的梦境啊
What an adorable dream!
再看看她
And look at her.
宝贵的孩子啊
Precious child.
这么可爱
So sweet.
充满希望  十分快乐
So full of hope and wonder.
就缺一样东西
Why, there's only one thing missing.
恐惧
A touch of fear.
恐惧是永恒的
That never gets old.
恐惧害怕吧  来吧  害怕就对了
Feel your fear. Come on. Come on, that's right.
多么可爱的噩梦啊
Yes, what a pretty little Nightmare!
现在
Now,
你去告诉其他人 我不会再等了
I want you to go tell the others the wait is over.
老朋友  别那么看着我
Don't look at me like that, old friend.
你肯定已经预见到了  这一天终将到来
You must have known this day would come.
我的噩梦都准备好了
My Nightmares are finally ready.
你的守护者们准备好了吗
Are your Guardians?
你好  伙计
Hello, mate.
好久不见
Been a long time.
上次见面还是68年的暴风雪吧
Blizzard of '68 I believe.
复活节那天  周日  没记错吧
Easter Sunday, wasn't it?
复活节兔  你不会还为那事儿记仇吧
Bunny! You're not still mad about that, are you?
我是记仇
Yes.
但今天却不是为了这件事
But this is about something else.
伙计们
Fellas?
放我下来  搞什么啊
Put me down! What the...
我
Me?
绝对不 北极见
Not on your nelly. See you back at the Pole.
他来了
He's here.
安静
Quiet.
他终于来了
There he is!
冰霜侠杰克
Jack Frost!
这是在做梦吧
You got to be kidding me.
传说中喜马拉雅山的雪人
-放我下来 -雪人没跟你动粗吧
-Put me down. -I hope the yetis treated you well.
被塞进袋子丢进魔法门的感觉真是好极了
I love being shoved in a sack and tossed through a magic portal.
那就好  这是我的主意
Oh, good. That was my idea!
复活节兔你是认识的
You know Bunny, obviously.
-当然认识 -这是牙仙
-Obviously. -And the Tooth Fairy.
你好  杰克  久仰大名
Hello, Jack. I've heard a lot about you.
当然还有你的牙
And your teeth!
我的什么
My what?
张开嘴  真像传说的那么白吗
Open up! Are they really as white as they say?
没错
Yes!
你的牙果真像初落的雪般洁白晶莹
They really do sparkle like freshly fallen snow!
姑娘们  镇定
Girls, pull yourselves together!
保持形象
Let's not disgrace the uniform.
这是睡神
And Sandman.
睡神
Sandy?
睡神 别睡了
Sandy? Wake up!
谁能告诉我  为什么我会在这儿
Anyone want to tell me why I'm here?
我看不太懂
That's not really helping,
不过还是谢谢你
but thanks, little man.
能把你们四个召集起来
I must've done something really bad
我肯定是做了什么坏事
to get you four together.
我在淘气榜上吗
Am I on the naughty list?
淘气榜上
On naughty list?
你确实是排名第一
You hold the record.
不过没关系  我们都不追究了
But, no matter. We overlook.
以前的事都一笔勾销
Now we are wiping clean the slate.
为什么
How come?
问得好
Good question.
为什么 我来给你解释
How come? I tell you how come!
因为从现在开始
Because now
你也是守护者的一员了
you are Guardian!
你要干什么  别碰我
What are you doing? Get off of me!
这才是最精彩的部分
This is the best part!
谁说我想成为守护者的
What makes you think I want to be a Guardian?
你当然想成为守护者
Of course you do.
音乐起
Music!
音乐停
No music!
虽然我觉得很受用  但是
This is all very flattering, but,
我跟你们根本不一样
you don't want me.
你们每天拼命工作  为最后期限努力
You're all hard work and deadlines,
而我只想打雪仗开心地玩
and I'm snowballs and fun times.
我才不是守护者
I'm not a Guardian.
是啊  早跟你说过吧
Yeah. That's exactly what I said.
杰克 我觉得你还没有明白我们的使命
Jack, I don't think you understand what it is we do.
这里的每一个光点都代表着一个孩子
Each of those lights is a child.
这些孩子相信我们
A child who believes.
不论好坏  不论听话还是淘气
And good or bad, naughty or nice,
都相信我们在保护他们
we protect them.
牙仙 把手从他嘴里拿出来
Tooth! Fingers out of mouth.
不好意思  你的牙实在是太漂亮了
Sorry. They're beautiful.
好了  别再说那些没用的
Okay. No more wishy-washy.
比奇来了  天知道他要做什么坏事
Pitch is out there doing who knows what!
你是说  黑暗梦魇来了
You mean the Boogeyman?
不错  比奇来威胁我们
Yes! When Pitch threatens us,
就会威胁孩子们
he threatens them as well.
那你们应该挑一个更合适的人啊
All the more reason to pick someone more qualified.
挑  你以为我们有权利挑人吗
Pick? You think we pick?
不  你跟我们一样  是被选中的
No, you were chosen! Like we were all chosen.
被月中人选中的
By Man in Moon.
什么
What?
杰克 昨天晚上他选中了你
Last night, Jack, he chose you.
也许吧
Maybe.
月中人  他跟你们说话了
Man in the Moon... He talks to you?
你不能拒绝
You see, you cannot say no.
这就是你的命运
It is destiny.
那为什么他不亲口告诉我呢
But why wouldn't he tell me that himself?
300年了  这就是他的回答吗
After 300 years this is his answer?
像你们一样长久存在
To spend eternity like you guys,
却藏在某个地方  想法设法收买孩子们
cooped up in some hideout thinking of new ways to bribe kids?
不不  我才不干  无意冒犯
No, no. That's not for me! No offense.
这还不算冒犯
How is that not offensive?
知道我怎么想的吗
You know what I think?
我觉得我们算是躲过一劫
I think we just dodged a bullet.
你们说  他知道
I mean, what's this clown
如何给孩子们带去欢乐吗
know about bringing joy to children anyway.
你听说过雪天吗
You ever hear of a snow day?
我知道雪天跟煮鸡蛋没什么关系
I know it's no hard-boiled egg,
不过孩子们都很喜欢雪天
but kids like what I do.
但没人相信你的存在  对吧
But none of them believe in you, do they?
伙计  没人看得到你
You see, you're invisible, mate.
就像从不存在一样
It's like you don't even exist.
复活节兔  够了
Bunny! Enough.
不  这只袋鼠说得对
No, the kangaroo's right.
这只什么  你说我是什么
The what? What did you call me?
我可不是袋鼠
I'm not a kangaroo, mate.
不过我一直以为你是
Oh, and this whole time I thought you were.
不是袋鼠的话 那你是什么
If you're not a kangaroo, what are you?
我是兔子  复活节兔子
I'm a bunny. The Easter Bunny.
人们都相信我的存在
People believe in me.
杰克 我们去走走
Jack. Walk with me.
我并不是针对某一个人  诺斯
It's nothing personal, North.
只是  你们做的事情  不适合我
But what you all do, it's just not my thing.
但月中人说这事适合你
Man in Moon says it is your thing!
我们拭目以待
We will see.
慢点  我想闯进来好久了
Slow down, would you? I've been trying to bust in here for years.
-让我好好参观一下 -什么  闯进来
-I want a good look. -What do you mean, bust in?
别担心  一直都还没过雪人那关
Don't worry. I never got past the yetis.
你好  菲尔
Hey, Phil.
跟上  杰克 跟上
Keep up, Jack, keep up!
我一直以为小精灵负责做玩具
I always thought the elves made the toys.
就让孩子们这么认为吧
We just let them believe that.
很漂亮 干得不错  继续吧
Very nice! Keep up good work.
那个颜色不好看  换成红色
I don't like it! Paint it red!
各位  加油吧
Step it up, everybody!
要来点水果蛋糕吗
Fruitcake?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
下面我们来讨论下实质问题
Now we get down to tacks of brass.
实质问题
Tacks of...
你是谁  冰霜侠杰克
Who are you, Jack Frost?
-你的本质如何  -我的本质
-What is your center? -My center?
既然你被月亮里的人选为守护者
If Man in Moon chose you to be a Guardian,
你内心深处肯定有某些特质
you must have something very special inside.
看
Here.
这就是你眼中的我吧
This is how you see me, no?
大块头  有点吓人
Very big, intimidating.
但如果你可以再深入了解我一些的话
But if you get to know me a little...
来  打开
Well, go on.
很明显  你很开心
You are downright jolly?
那可不仅仅是开心
But not just jolly!
我还很神秘
I am also mysterious,
无所畏惧
and fearless,
很有爱心
and caring!
而我的本质
And at my center?
是个小木娃娃
There's a tiny wooden baby.
再仔细看看 你看到了什么
Look closer. What do you see?
眼睛挺大的
You have big eyes.
对  就是大眼睛
Yes! Big eyes. Very big.
非常大的眼睛  因为我的眼中充满好奇
Because they are full of wonder.
那就是我的本质
That is my center.
这是我与生俱来的
It is what I was born with.
眼中能看到所有事物的美妙
Eyes that have always seen the wonder in everything!
我可以看到树上的灯光  空中的魔法
Eyes that see lights in the trees and magic in the air.
这些美妙的东西都是我献给这世界的
This wonder is what I put into the world!
也是我极力想让孩子们保留的
And what I protect in children.
也是我成为守护者的原因
It is what makes me a Guardian.
这就是我的本质
It is my center.
你的本质是什么样的呢
What is yours?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们有麻烦了  老大
We have a problem, mate.
牙仙宫殿出事了
Trouble at the Tooth Palace.
诺斯  诺斯
North! North!
我告诉你  我不会跟你们去的
I told you I'm not going with you guys!
我才不会坐这辆旧的快散架的
There is no way I'm climbing into some rickety old...
雪橇
...Sleigh?
好吧  我就坐一次  就一次
Okay. One ride, but that's it.
人人都爱圣诞老人的雪橇
Everyone loves the sleigh!
复活节兔  你还在等什么
Bunny, what are you waiting for?
我还是觉得我的兔子洞更快 更安全
I think my tunnels might be faster, mate, and safer.
上车吧你
Get in!
系好安全带
Buckle up!
等下  安全带在哪里
Where are the bloody seatbelts?
只是说说而已  准备好了吗
That was just expression. Are we ready?
准备好了吗 出发啦
Good. Let's go! Clear!
快让开
Out of the way!
救命
Oh, no!
慢点  慢点
Slow down! Slow down!
这车还坐得惯吧
I hope you like the loopty-loops.
让你吃胡萝卜看你惯不惯
I hope you like carrots.
要起飞啦
Here we go!
腾空起飞
Blastoff!
兔子
Bunny.
看看这景色
Check out this view.
诺斯  他掉下去了
North! He's...
你还是在意我的嘛
You do care.
一边去  爱闹腾的小鬼
Rack off, you bloody show pony!
都扶好了  我知道条捷径
Hold on, everyone! I know a shortcut.
我的天  我就知道应该走地道的
Strewth, I knew I should've taken the tunnels.
去牙齿宫殿
I say Tooth Palace.
什么
What?
这是什么
What are they?
他们在抓小牙仙
They're taking the tooth fairies!
牙仙宝宝  你没事吧
Little Baby Tooth, you okay?
接着  你来驾车
Here, take over.
他们在偷牙齿
They're stealing the teeth!
杰克 看路
Jack, look out!
牙仙 你还好吗
Tooth! Are you all right?
他们抓走了小牙仙
They... They took my fairies.
还夺走了牙齿  所有的小牙仙和牙齿
And the teeth! All of them!
什么都没了
Everything is gone.
都没了
Everything.
谢天谢地  还有个牙仙宝宝没事
Oh, thank goodness. One of you is all right.
我得说 真让人激动啊
I have to say, this is very, very exciting.
四名守护者齐聚一堂
The Big Four, all in one place.
我可是个小粉丝呢
I'm a little starstruck.
北极的那出戏你还喜欢吗  诺斯
Did you like my show on the Globe, North?
让你们聚到了一起  对吧
Got you all together, didn't I?
比奇  30秒内放了小牙仙
Pitch! You have got 30 seconds to return my fairies!
不然怎样呢
Or what?
你要偷走我枕头下的硬币吗
You'll stick a quarter under my pillow?
为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
也许  我想取代你们
Maybe I want what you have.
让孩子们相信我的存在
To be believed in.
也许  我受够了躲在床下
Maybe I'm tired of hiding under beds!
也许  你就应该待在那里
Maybe that's where you belong!
吃你的蛋去  兔子
Go suck an egg, rabbit.
等等  这不是冰霜侠杰克吗
Hang on. Is that Jack Frost?
你什么时候和他们这么亲密了
Since when are you all so chummy?
我们没有
We're not.
很好  中立党啊
Good. A neutral party.
那我就忽略你好了
Then I'm going to ignore you.
你现在也习惯被忽视了吧
But you must be used to that by now.
比奇  你这个偷偷摸摸的混蛋  过来
Pitch, you shadow-sneaking ratbag, come here!
别激动  姑娘 别激动
Hey! Easy, girl, easy.
这东西眼熟吧  睡神
Look familiar, Sandman?
花了不少功夫呢
Took me a while to perfect this little trick.
把梦境变成噩梦
Turning dreams into Nightmares.
别紧张
Don't be nervous.
这样只会激怒它们 它们能闻到恐惧
It only riles them up more. They smell fear, you know.
有什么好恐惧的  你吗
What fear? Of you?
黑暗时代之后  就没人怕你了
No one's been afraid of you since the Dark Ages!
黑暗时代啊
The Dark Ages.
所有人都生活在恐惧  痛苦之中
Everyone frightened. Miserable.
多么美好的时光啊
Such happy times for me.
还有那源源不断的力量
The power I wielded.
然后月中人选择了你们
But then the Man in the Moon
用神奇和光明取代了对我的恐惧
chose you to replace my fear with your wonder and light.
给他们信心  给他们希望
Lifting their hearts and giving them hope.
人们只当我是不开心的梦境
Meanwhile, everyone wrote me off as just a bad dream!
"没什么好怕的
"There's nothing to be afraid of.
根本就没有黑暗梦魇嘛"
There's no such thing as the Boogeyman!"
这一切都将改变
Well, that's all about to change.
听着
Look.
好戏已经开始了
It's happening already.
怎么回事
What is?
孩子们醒来  发现
Children are waking up and realizing
牙仙没来过
the Tooth Fairy never came.
虽然是小事  但在孩子眼里...
I mean, such a little thing. But to a child...
发生什么了
What's going on?
他们  他们不再相信我了
They... They don't believe in me anymore.
他们告诉过你吗  杰克
Didn't they tell you, Jack?
当守护者很棒
It's great being a Guardian.
但是他们有个弱点
But there's a catch.
如果孩子们不再相信你们
If enough kids stop believing,
你的朋友所保护的一切
everything your friends protect,
神奇  希望和梦想  一切都将消失
wonder, hopes and dreams, it all goes away.
一点点地消失  他们也是一样
And little by little, so do they.
没有圣诞节  复活节也没有
No Christmas or Easter,
会在夜间出现的精灵
or little fairies that come in the night.
除了恐惧和黑暗  一切都将消失
There will be nothing but fear and darkness.
当然  还有我
And me.
轮到没人相信你们了
It's your turn not to be believed in.
他跑了
He's gone.
好吧  我承认
Okay, all right, I admit it.
关于比奇的事  你说的没错
You were right about Pitch.
精灵们被抓走了  我很遗憾
I'm sorry about the fairies.
你应该看看他们 他们拼命战斗
You should have seen them. They put up such a fight.
比奇为什么要夺走牙齿
Why would Pitch take the teeth?
他要的不是牙齿
It's not the teeth he wanted.
而是其中的记忆
It's the memories inside them.
什么意思
What do you mean?
这才是我们搜集牙齿的原因  杰克
That's why we collect the teeth, Jack.
牙齿里有童年最宝贵的记忆
They hold the most important memories of childhood.
我和精灵们保管着这些记忆
My fairies and I watch over them.
当有人想回忆起对他们最重要的事
And when someone needs to remember what's important,
我们就会帮助他们
we help them.
所有人的都在这里
We had everyone's here.
也包括你的
Yours, too.
我的记忆吗
My memories?
是你小时候的记忆
From when you were young.
是你成为冰霜侠杰克前的记忆
Before you became Jack Frost.
可在成为冰霜侠杰克前 我谁也不是
But I wasn't anyone before I was Jack Frost.
怎么会呢
Of course you were.
在被选中前  我们都有身份
We were all someone before we were chosen.
什么
What?
你应该看看的  复活节兔
You should have seen Bunny.
我叫你别提那件事的
I told you never to mention that!
在湖边的那晚  我以为...
The night at the pond, I just... I assumed...
你是说
Are you saying...
你是说我也像常人一样生活吗
Are you saying I had a life before that,
在这之前 我有过家 有过家人吗
with a home and a family?
你真的不记得了吗
You really don't remember?
这些年来  答案就在这里
All these years, the answers were right here.
如果找到记忆
If I find my memories,
那我就知道我为什么会在这里了
then I'll know why I'm here.
你得给我看看
You have to show me!
我办不到  杰克 记忆在比奇手上
I can't, Jack. Pitch has them.
那我们就把记忆夺回来
Then we have to get them back!
不
Oh, no.
孩子们...
The children!
已经太迟了
We're too late!
不 不
No! No!
没有太迟了这回事
No such thing as too late!
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
有办法了
Idea!
我们去搜集牙齿
We will collect the teeth.
什么
What?
我们去搜集牙齿 孩子们就会相信你了
We get teeth, children keep believing in you!
这可是七大洲  几百万个孩子啊
We're talking seven continents and millions of kids!
得了吧
Give me break.
你知道我一晚上要送出多少玩具吗
You know how many toys I deliver in one night?
知道我一天内又要藏多少个彩蛋吗
And eggs I hide in one day?
杰克 如果你帮我们
And, Jack, if you help us,
我们就帮你找回你的记忆
we will get you your memories.
算我一个
I'm in.
快  快
Quickly! Quickly!
快跳呀兔子  我已经领先五颗牙齿了
Hop to it, rabbit! I'm five teeth ahead!
我还想你别挡路呢
Yeah, right. Look, I'd tell you to stay out of my way,
但你知道关键是什么吗
but, really, what's the point?
我会追上你的
'Cause you won't be able to keep up anyway.
这是在发起挑战吗  灰兔子
Is that a challenge, cottontail?
你可别和兔子赛跑  伙计
You don't want to race a rabbit, mate.
赛跑  这是赛跑吗
A race? Is it a race?
这将是一场史诗般的赛跑
This is going to be epic!
这里有四颗虎牙
Four bicuspids over there!
东边两个街区外有一颗门牙
An incisor two blocks east.
那是颗臼齿吗  到处都是牙齿耶
Is that a molar? They're everywhere!
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  抱歉
I'm fine. Sorry.
我只是好久没出过外勤了
It's been a really long time since I've been out in the field.
好久是多久
How long is a long time?
440年  左右吧
440 years, give or take.
两颗
Twins!
大金矿啊
Jackpot!
最近不太小心啊  小朋友
Looks like you're a bit of a brumby,mate?
找到了
Is piece of pie.
那是我的牙齿  睡神  睡神
That's my tooth! Sandy! Sandy!
别激动  小家伙
Take it easy there, champ.
他也是我们中的一员 欧洲分部的
He's one of us! Part of the European division.
哎呀呀
Crikey!
归我啦
Yes!
不
No!
你们搜集牙齿留下礼物的速度
Wow! You guys collect teeth and leave gifts
和我的精灵一样快耶
as fast as my fairies.
你们留了礼物  对吧
You guys have been leaving gifts, right?
这些光芒
The lights.
为什么又亮起来了
Why aren't they going out?
他们在搜集牙齿
They're collecting the teeth?
安静  要不就把你们做成枕头
Pipe down or I'll stuff a pillow with you!
行  你们再垂死挣扎一下吧
Fine. Have your last hurrah.
明天...
For tomorrow,
你们无助的挣扎都将化为云烟
all your pathetic scrambling will be for nothing.
左中切牙
Left central incisor,
在一次雪橇事故中被撞掉
knocked out in a freak sledding accident.
这是怎么发生的呢  杰克
I wonder how that could've happened, Jack.
孩子嘛
Kids?
这一直是我最喜欢的事情
This was always the part I liked most.
看着孩子...
Seeing the kids.
我为什么没一直干下去呢
Why did I ever stop doing this?
靠进看的感觉不太一样  对吧
It's a little different up close, huh?
谢谢你陪着我  杰克
Thanks for being here, Jack.
真希望我知道你的记忆
I wish I'd known about your memory.
那样就能帮上你了
I could have helped you.
是啊
Yeah...
先把牙齿收集好
Look, let's just get you taken care of.
我们就去对付比奇
Then it's Pitch's turn.
你们在这里啊
Here you are!
老人家嘛  动作慢
What gives, slowpokes?
感觉怎么样  牙仙
How you feeling, Toothy?
被相信着
Believed in.
我就想听这句话
That's what I want to hear.
我明白了  你们合起伙儿来
I see how it is. All working together
好让兔子我变成最后一名
to make sure the rabbit gets last place.
你以为打败只兔子还需要帮手吗
You think I need help to beat a bunny?
看看  灰尾巴
Check it out, Peter Cottontail.
你这也能叫一袋牙齿吗
You call that a bag of choppers?
不  这才叫一袋牙齿
Now that's a bag of choppers.
先生们 先生们  我们是来搜集牙齿的
Gentlemen, gentlemen. This is about Tooth.
不是来比赛的
It's not a competition.
是搜集牙齿  不是比赛哦
But if it was, I win!
哦不
Oh, no.
圣诞老人
Santa Claus?
复活节兔子
The Easter Bunny?
睡神
Sandman?
牙仙 我就知道你会来的
The Tooth Fairy! I knew you'd come!
我们来了  惊喜吧
Surprise! We came.
他能看见我们吗
He can see us?
大部分能看见
Most of us.
小声点  他还醒着呢
You guys, he's still awake.
睡神  把他敲昏
Sandy, knock him out.
用梦沙  笨蛋
With the Dreamsand, you gumbies!
别过去  那是复活节兔子
No, stop! That's the Easter Bunny!
你在干什么  艾比  坐下
What are you doing, Abbey? Down!
别动  都别慌
All right, nobody panic.
可这是  这是只灰狗
But that's a greyhound.
你知道灰狗会怎么对付兔子吗
Do you know what greyhounds do to rabbits?
没事的  他从没见过我这样的兔子
I think it's a pretty safe bet he's never met a rabbit like me.
身高一米八
Six-foot-one,
钢铁般的意志
nerves of steel.
太极高手  还是...
Master of tai-chi and the ancient art of...
停下  坐下
Stop! Sit!
姑娘  坐下
Down, girl, down!
快  睡神 睡神
Sandy!
这家伙真暴躁  把这野狗拉开
She's rabid! Get this dingo off me!
字幕
Oh, no.
拐杖糖
Candy canes...
要是带相机了就好了
I really wish I had a camera right now.
睡神  快来  我们能找到比奇
Sandy, come on! We can find Pitch!
漂漂
Pretty.
兔兔  跳跳跳
Bunny, hop, hop, hop!
怎么了
What...
棒极了
Yes!
我抓到它了
I got it.
睡神
Sandy!
睡神  看到了吗
Sandy, did you see that?
看看这东西
Look at this thing.
冰霜侠
Frost?
要知道 作为中立人员
You know, for a neutral party,
你和那些怪胎过于亲密了
you spend an awful lot of time with those weirdos.
你不该趟这浑水  杰克
This isn't your fight, Jack.
你偷了我的牙齿  就是对我宣战
You made it my fight when you stole those teeth!
牙齿  为什么这么在意牙齿呢
Teeth? Why do you care about the teeth?
我正找你呢
Now this is who I'm looking for.
记得提醒我  别跟你作对
Remind me not to get on your bad side.
别生气 这不能怪我  睡神
Okay, easy. You can't blame me for trying, Sandy.
你不知道力量弱小 又被讨厌的感觉
You don't know what it's like to be weak and hated.
扰乱你的梦境是我不对
It was stupid of me to mess with your dreams.
听我说
So, I'll tell you what.
从后面袭击
You can have them back.
你解决左边的
You take the ones on the left,
我解决右边的
I'll take the ones on the right?
放马过来吧
Come on!
你最好蹲下
You might want to duck.
我们得帮帮睡神
We've got to help Sandy!
不
No!
杰克
Jack!
不要抗争恐惧  小个子
Don't fight the fear, little man!
快  快  杰克
Hurry! Hurry, Jack!
我想说"祝你美梦"
I'd say "Sweet dreams,"
只可惜  美梦已经消失了
But there aren't any left.
睡神
Sandy?
不
No!
杰克
Jack!
杰克 你怎么做到的
Jack, how did you do that?
我也不知道
I didn't know I could.
终于
Finally!
终于有人能让我开心下了
Someone who knows how to have a little fun!
你还好吗
Are you all right?
我只是
I just...
我希望我当时能帮上忙
I wish I could've done something.
帮上忙
Done something?
杰克 你勇敢地和比奇战斗
Jack, you stood up to Pitch.
你救了我们
You saved us!
但是睡神他
But Sandy...
他会以你为荣
Would be proud of what you did.
我不知道你原来是什么人
I don't know who you were in your past life.
但现在  你是一名守护者
But in this life, you are Guardian.
不知道我的过去  怎么能知道我是谁呢
But how can I know who I am until I find out who I was?
你会知道的
You will.
我能感觉到
I feel it
用我的肚子
in my belly.
你看这些光芒熄灭的速度
Look how fast they're going out.
是恐惧
It's fear.
是他搞的鬼
He's tipped the balance.
退后  你们真没出息
Hey, buck up, you sad sacks!
我们还有机会扭转局面
We can still turn this around!
明天就是复活节了
Easter is tomorrow.
我需要你们的帮助
And I need your help.
我说我们全力以赴
I say we pull out all the stops
让这些光芒再次闪烁起来
and we get those little lights flickering again.
兔子说的没错
Bunny is right.
尽管说出来很难受  朋友
As much as it pains me to say, old friend,
但这一次  复活节比圣诞节更重要
this time, Easter is more important than Christmas.
你们都听到了吗
Hey, did everyone hear that?
我们得赶快去你的养蛋场
We must hurry to the warren.
大家都上雪橇
Everyone! To the sleigh!
不  兄弟  我的地盘 我做主
No, mate. My warren, my rules.
系好安全带
Buckle up.
我的老天
Shostakovich!
系好安全带 真好笑
"Buckle up." Is very funny.
欢迎来到养蛋场
Welcome to the warren.
有什么事不对
Something's up.
索菲
Sophie?
-小精灵  精灵  -她怎么会在这里
-Elf, elf, elf! -What is she doing here?
世界地球村
Snow globe.
快想想办法
Somebody do something.
别看我  她看不见我  记得吗
Don't look at me. I'm invisible, remember?
精灵  精灵
Elf! Elf!
别担心  兔子  我肯定她是个精灵粉
Don't worry, Bunny. I bet she's a fairy fan.
-别害怕  小家伙 -漂漂
-It's okay, little one. -Pretty.
知道吗  我有东西给你
You know what? I've got something for you!
就是它们
Here it is!
看看这些漂亮的牙齿
Look at all the pretty teeth,
上面还沾着血和口香糖
with little blood and gum on them!
血和口香糖
Blood and gums?
你们上次和孩子们玩耍
When was the last time
到底是什么时候
you guys actually hung out with kids?
躲猫猫
Peek-a-boo!
我们很忙 忙着给孩子们带去欢乐
We are very busy bringing joy to children.
我们没时间...
We don't have time...
跟孩子们玩
For children.
如果一个小孩子就能毁掉复活节
If one little kid can ruin Easter,
那我们也太差劲了吧
then we're in worse shape than I thought.
你想涂颗彩蛋吗
You want to paint some eggs? Yeah?
-想  -跟我来吧
-Okay. -Come on.
我的天
Rimsky-Korsakov!
这么多蛋
That's a lot of eggs.
我们还有多长时间来着
How much time do we have?
好了  战友们  是时候反击了
All right, troops, it's time to push back.
换句话说  彩蛋要无处不在
That means eggs everywhere!
你们要侵入每栋高楼
Heaps of you in every high-rise,
每个农场 每个拖车公园
farmhouse, and trailer park!
藏到网球鞋里  藏到麦片罐子里
In tennis shoes and cereal bowls.
浴缸也要装满我美丽的彩蛋
Oh, there will be bathtubs filled with my beautiful googies!
这个  有点奇怪
Okay, that's a little strange.
不  朋友
No, mate.
他们可爱极了
That's adorable.
春色照大地  各大洲都将春意盎然
There will be springtime! On every continent!
而我  将为他们带去希望
And I'm bringing hope with me!
太圣诞了  朋友  涂蓝色
Too Christmas-y, mate. Paint them blue.
那里是什么
What's over there?
真漂亮
That's a beauty!
现在我们只要把他和小家伙
Now, all we got to do is get him and his little mates
通过隧道送回去
through the tunnels to the top
然后复活节就是我们的了
and we'll have ourselves Easter.
不赖啊
Not bad.
你也不赖
Not bad yourself.
我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry about the whole...
那个  说你是袋鼠
You know, the kangaroo thing.
是因为口音吧[兔子先生带有澳洲口音]
It's the accent, isn't it?
可怜的小家伙  都累坏了
Poor little ankle-biter. Look at her. All tuckered out.
我爱她
I love her.
我想是时候送她回家了
I think it's time to get her home.
不如我送她回家吧
How about I take her home?
杰克 不  比奇就在外...
Jack, no. Pitch is...
他打不赢这个
No match for this.
正因为这样  我们需要你和我们在一起
Which is why we need you here with us.
相信我  我会和兔子跑得一样快的
Trust me. I'll be quick as a bunny.
索菲  是你吗
Sophie? Is that you?
我们该回去了
We should get back.
杰克
Jack!
那个声音  我认得那个声音
That voice, I know that voice.
杰克
Jack!
别担心  还有时间
Don't worry, there's still time.
杰克
Jack?
牙仙宝宝 小家伙  别闹
Baby Tooth, come on!
我得看看这是怎么回事
I have to find out what that is.
小声点
Keep it down!
我会救你们出去  我会...
I'm gonna get you out of here just as soon as...
杰克
Jack?
Jack!
尽快救你们...
...As I can.
你在找什么
Looking for something?
别害怕  杰克  我不会伤害你的
Don't be afraid, Jack. I'm not gonna hurt you.
怕  我才不怕你
Afraid? I'm not afraid of you.
也许是这样 但是你也有害怕的东西
Maybe not. But you are afraid of something.
-你这么想吗 -我知道
-You think so, huh? -I know so!
我一直都知道的
It's the one thing I always know.
就是人们最恐惧的东西
People's greatest fears.
你最恐惧的是  没人会再相信你
Yours is that no one will ever believe in you.
而更让你恐惧的是
And worst of all,
你永远都不会知道原因
you're afraid you'll never know why.
为什么是你
Why you?
为什么选了你 成为现在这样
Why were you chosen to be like this?
别害怕
Fear not.
答案  就在这里
For the answer to that is right here.
杰克 你想要吗  你的记忆
Do you want them, Jack? Your memories?
你想知道的一切都在这个小盒子里
Everything you wanted to know, in this little box.
你怎么会沦落至此 没人能看得见
Why did you end up like this? Unseen.
没人能触摸到
Unable to reach out to anyone.
你那么想知道答案
You want the answers so badly.
你想带着答案马上逃开
You want to grab them and fly off with them.
但是你又在意其他守护者的想法
But you're afraid of what the Guardians will think.
你怕让他们失望
You're afraid of disappointing them.
让我来开解你吧
Let me ease your mind about one thing.
他们永远不会真正接受你
They'll never accept you. Not really.
停下  快停下
Stop it! Stop it!
毕竟  你不是他们中的一员
After all, you're not one of them.
你根本不知道我是谁
You don't know what I am.
我当然知道  你是冰霜侠杰克
Of course I do! You're Jack Frost.
你走到哪里都是一团糟
You make a mess wherever you go.
现在也一样
Why, you're doing it right now.
你做了什么
What did you do?
重要的是   杰克  你做了什么
More to the point, Jack, what did you do?
小牙仙
Baby Tooth!
复活节快乐  杰克
Happy Easter, Jack.
不
No.
寻找复活节彩蛋
这里没有彩蛋
There aren't any eggs.
-这里什么都没有  -我放弃了
-There's nothing here. -I give up.
-他没来  -我不明白
-He didn't come. -I don't understand.
也许只是今年藏得特别好
Maybe he just hid them really well this year.
-小子    -我哪都找过了
-Kids! -I checked everywhere.
什么都没有
There's nothing.
在这儿  在这儿
Yes, there is! There is!
虽然这不是我最好的作品
I mean, these aren't my best looking googies,
不过也不赖啊
but they'll do in a pinch.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我  我知道
I know.
根本没有什么复活节兔子
There's no such thing as the Easter Bunny.
什么  不
What? No.
这不是真的
Wrong! Not true!
我就在你们面前  伙计
I'm right in front of you, mate.
他们看不见我
Why wouldn't he come?
They don't see me.
杰克 你去哪里了
Jack, where were you?
那些梦魇攻击了隧道
The Nightmares attacked the tunnels.
打碎了每个鸡蛋 弄坏了每个篮子
They smashed every egg, crushed every basket.
没有彩蛋到达地面
Nothing made it to the surface.
杰克
Jack.
你从哪里拿到的
Where did you get that?
是从...其实...
I was... Lt's...
小牙仙呢
Where's Baby Tooth?
杰克 你做了什么
Jack, what have you done?
难怪你昨天不在
That is why you weren't here?
你和比奇在一起吗
You were with Pitch?
不  听我说  听我说
No, listen, listen.
我很抱歉  我没想到会发生这些
I'm sorry. I didn't mean for this to happen.
-他必须离开 -什么
-He has to go. -What?
我们根本就不该信你
We should never have trusted you!
复活节是新开始  新生命
Easter is new beginnings, new life.
复活节就是希望
Easter's about hope.
现在没有了
And now it's gone.
我们再去检查一次公园
Let's check the park again.
-不是吧 -找什么  复活节兔子吗
-Really? -For what? The Easter Bunny?
伙计们  我说过  我看过他
Guys, I told you, I saw him!
他比我想象得要大
He's way bigger than I thought
还有个超酷的回旋镖之类的东西
and he's got these cool boomerang things!
成熟点吧  杰米
Grow up, Jamie.
兄弟  不是吧
Oh, man. Seriously?
你们怎么了
What's happened to you guys?
那只是个梦
It was a dream!
你该高兴自己还能有那样的梦
You should be happy you still get dreams like that
而不是...
and not...
噩梦
Nightmares.
算了吧  杰米
Forget it, Jamie.
今年没有复活节
There's just no Easter this year.
他确实是真的
He really is real!
我知道他是
I know he is.
我就猜会这样
I thought this might happen.
他们从来没有真正地相信过你
They never really believed in you.
我只是想试着告诉你
I was just trying to show you that.
但是我懂
But I understand.
你什么都不懂
You don't understand anything!
你以为我不懂被排除在外的感觉吗
No? I don't know what it's like to be cast out?
不懂不被信任的感觉吗
To not be believed in?
不懂一直想要一个家的感觉吗
To long for a family.
这么多年隐藏在黑暗里
All those years in the shadows I thought
我一直以为没人能理解这种感觉
no one else knows what this feels like.
但现在看来我错了
But now I see I was wrong.
我们没必要独自前行  杰克
We don't have to be alone, Jack.
我相信你 孩子们也会相信的
I believe in you. And I know children will, too.
相信我吗
In me?
是的
Yes!
看看我们一起能做些什么
Look at what we can do.
还有什么比寒冷和黑暗结合得更好呢
What goes together better than cold and dark?
我们会让他们相信
We can make them believe.
我们可以给他们一个世界  充满了
We'll give them a world where everything, everything is...
黑暗梦魇
Pitch black?
还有冰霜侠杰克
And Jack Frost, too.
孩子们会相信我们两个
They'll believe in both of us.
不  他们会怕我们两个
No, they'll fear both of us.
那不是我想要的
And that's not what I want.
最后说一次
Now for the last time,
让我一个人呆着
leave me alone.
好  你想一个人呆着
Very well. You want to be left alone.
没问题  不过首先
Done. But first...
牙仙宝宝
Baby Tooth!
给我手杖  杰克
The staff, Jack!
你总是喜欢打扰别人
You have a bad habit of interfering.
现在把手杖给我 我就放她走
Now, hand it over, and I'll let her go.
好了
All right.
现在放她走
Now let her go.
不行
No.
你说想一个人呆着
You said you wanted to be alone.
那就一个人呆着吧
So be alone!
不
No!
牙仙宝宝
Baby Tooth!
你还好吗
You all right?
抱歉 我只会让你感到寒冷
Sorry. All I can do is keep you cold.
比奇说得对
Pitch was right.
一切都让我搞砸了
I make a mess of everything.
杰克
Jack?
Jack!
杰克 快下来
Come on, Jack,
你不能一直玩
you can't have fun all the time.
杰克  下来
Jack, get down from there.
-杰克  -你真有意思  杰克
-Jack! -You're funny, Jack.
小心点
Be careful.
好的
We will.
没事的  没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
别向下看  看着我
Don't look down. Just look at me.
杰克
Jack.
我害怕
I'm scared.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
不过你会没事的  你不会掉下去的
But you're gonna be all right. You're not gonna fall in.
我们来好好玩一玩
We're gonna have a little fun instead!
不会的
No, we're not!
我会骗你吗
Would I trick you?
会  你一直恶作剧
Yes! You always play tricks!
好吧  不过这次不是
Well, not this time.
我保证  我保证
I promise, I promise. You're gonna be...
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
你得相信我
You have to believe in me.
想玩个游戏吗 我们来玩跳房子
You want to play a game? We're gonna play hopscotch!
就像我们每天玩得一样
Like we play every day.
很简单
It's as easy as
一
one...
二
Two.
三
Three!
好了
All right.
轮到你了
Now it's your turn.
一
One...
就这样  就这样
That's it, that's it.
二
Two.
三
Three!
杰克
Jack!
你看见  你看见了吗
Did you see... Did you see that?
那是我
It was me!
我有个家  我还有个妹妹
I had a family! I had a sister!
我救了她
I saved her!
所以你才会选择我
That's why you chose me.
我是个守护者
I'm a Guardian.
我们得离开这里
We have to get out of here.
好的
Okay.
走吧  牙仙宝宝  我欠你一次
Come on, Baby Tooth, I owe you one!
来吧  我们走
Come on! Let's go!
怎么了
What's wrong?
你们都飞不起来了吗
None of you can fly?
那些光点
The lights.
你们都可以走了
You're all free to go!
今年不需要圣诞礼物了
We won't be needing any Christmas toys this year,
谢谢
thank you.
以后也不需要了
Nor ever again.
它们都熄灭了
They're all going out.
只有六个留下了
Only six left.
六个珍贵的孩子
Six precious children
还傻傻地相信守护者存在
who still believe in the Guardians with all their hearts.
让它变成
Make that
五个吧
five.
四
Four.
三
Three!
二
Two!
一
One.
杰米
Jamie.
听着
Okay, look,
我们现在处在人生的十字路口上
you and I are obviously at what they call a crossroads.
这样吧
So here's what's gonna happen.
如果那不是梦  如果你是真的
If it wasn't a dream and if you are real
你就得证明  现在  马上
then you have to prove it, like, right now.
我一直都相信你
I've believed in you for a long time, okay?
事实上  我一生都相信你存在
Like, my whole life, in fact.
所以你算是欠我的
So you kind of owe me now.
不必费事
You don't have to do much.
只要给我一个信号  让我知道
Just a little sign so I know.
任何事
Anything.
任何事都可以
Anything at all.
我就知道是假的
I knew it.
他是真的
He's real!
雪花
Snow?
冰霜侠杰克
Jack Frost.
他刚才说什么
Did he just say...
冰霜侠杰克
Jack Frost?
他又说了一次 他说
He said it again. He said...
你说
You said...
冰霜侠杰克
Jack Frost!
没错
That's right!
那是我 冰霜侠杰克 那是我的名字
But that's me! Jack Frost! That's my name!
你喊了我的名字
You said my name!
等等  你能听见我吗
Wait. Can you hear me?
你能看见我吗
Can you... Can you see me?
他能看见我 他能看见我
He sees me! He sees me!
-你制造了雪花 -是的
-You just made it snow! -I know!
-在我房间里 -是的
-In my room! -I know!
-你是真的吗  -当然
-You're real? -Yeah!
你觉得是谁制造了暴风雪和下雪天
Who do you think brings you all the blizzards and the snow days?
你还记得你在路上滑雪玩吗
And you remember when you went flying on that sled the other day?
-那是你吗 -那是我啊
-That was you? -That was me!
-真棒  -当然
-Cool! -Right?
那复活节兔呢  还有牙仙  还有
But what about the Easter Bunny? And the Tooth Fairy?
真的  真的  我们都是真的
Real, real, real! Every one of us is real.
-我就知道 -杰米  你在跟谁说话呢
-I knew it! -Jamie, who are you talking to?
冰霜侠杰克
Jack Frost?
好吧
Okay.
快回来
Come back!
-诺斯  你没事吧  -郑重声明
-North, are you okay? -Is official.
我的魔法有点失灵
My powers are kaput.
快看
Look!
杰克
Jack!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
你怎么会来这里
What are you doing here?
和你一样
Same as you.
最后一点光
The last light.
是你 真的是你
It is you! I mean, it is you!
我就知道那不是梦
I knew it wasn't a dream!
杰克 他能看见你
Jack, he sees you.
等一下  复活节兔呢
Wait. But where's Bunny?
失去复活节对我们都有影响
Losing Easter took its toll on all of us.
不过对复活节兔的影响最大
Bunny most of all.
不是吧
No.
你就是复活节兔
That's the Easter Bunny?
现在倒是有人能看见我了
Now somebody sees me!
老兄  你一小时之前在哪里呢
Where were you about an hour ago, mate?
他怎么了
What happened to him?
他以前很高  很酷  现在就
He used to be huge and cool. And now he's...
很可爱
Cute.
感觉真好
That's good.
是你让他这么说的吗
Did you tell him to say that? That's it!
走吧  就我们俩  做个了断
Let's go! Me and you! Come on!
不  事实上是他告诉我你是真的
No. Actually, he told me you were real.
就在我开始怀疑也许你不存在时候
Just when I started to think that maybe you weren't.
他让你相信
He made you believe?
相信我
In me?
带杰米离开这
Get Jamie out of here.
小心点  杰克
Be careful, Jack.
冰霜侠杰克
Jack Frost.
让我们做个了断吧
Let's end this, shall we?
这种小把戏对我已经没用了
That little trick doesn't work on me anymore.
这边  这边
This way, this way.
是条死路  那边  那边
Dead end. Other way, other way!
杰克
Jack!
做得好  杰克  努力成绩优异
That was good try, Jack. "A" For effort.
他变强了 我打不过他
He's stronger. I can't beat him.
这个小男孩就可以终结一切混乱
All this fuss over one little boy,
但他还坚持相信
and still he refuses to stop believing.
非常好
Very well.
还有别的方法可以熄灭光亮
There are other ways to snuff out a light.
想伤害他就得先过得我这关
If you want him, you're gonna have to go through me.
瞧瞧你多可爱啊
Look how fluffy you are.
你喜欢被人挠耳朵后面吗
Would you like a scratch behind the ears?
想都别想
Don't you even think about it.
你们不知道我看到你们变成这样有多开心
I can't tell you how happy it makes me to see you all like this.
你们看起来糟透了
You look awful.
杰克 我害怕
Jack. I'm scared.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
但是你会没事的
But you're gonna be all right.
我们来好好玩一玩
We're gonna have a little fun instead.
就是这样 这就是我的本质
That's it! That's my center!
你怎么想  杰米
So what do you think, Jamie?
你还相信这些小丑...
Do you believe in the Boogey...
让我们去找你的朋友们吧
Now let's go get your friends.
太好啦
Cool!
杰米  你是怎么做到的
Jamie, how are you doing that?
冰霜侠杰克
Jack Frost!
来吧  我们需要你们的帮助
Come on, we need your help!
那不就是
Is that...
冰霜侠杰克
Jack Frost!
-圣诞快乐 -还有复活节快乐
-Merry Christmas! -Happy Easter!
别忘了用牙线
Don't forget to floss!
-虎妞  -什么
-Cupcake? -What?
杰米  你是对的
Jamie, you were right!
复活节兔子是真的
The Easter Bunny's real!
-牙仙  -还有圣诞老人
-The Tooth Fairy! -And Santa!
都是真的
They're all real!
你们以为靠几个孩子就能力挽狂澜吗
You think a few children can help you? Against this?
那只是噩梦  杰米
They're just bad dreams, Jamie.
我们会保护你的  兄弟
And we'll protect you, mate.
你来保护他们
You'll protect them?
那谁来保护你呢
But who will protect you?
我来
I will.
-我来 -算上我
-I will. -I will.
我也是
And me.
我试试
I'll try.
你们还不相信黑暗梦魇吗
Still think there's no such thing as the Boogeyman?
我相信 但我并不怕你
I do believe in you. I'm just not afraid of you.
牙仙  好棒
Yeah, Tooth Fairy!
不 抓住他们
No! Get them!
拿下他们
Do your jobs!
加油  快变身  快点
Yeah, come on, come on.
天啊
Crikey!
真神奇
No way!
我只是只小兔子
I'm just a bunny!
晚上好啊  伙计
G'day, mate.
上啊
Come on!
打倒他们
Let's get them!
大伙上啊  我们能行
Come on, guys, we can do it!
交给你啦  伙计
It's all yours, mate.
谢啦  牙仙
Thanks, Tooth.
钻错烟囱了
Wrong roof.
看啊
Look at that!
我明白了
I got it!
我知道我们要做什么了
I know what we have to do.
伙伴们  走吧
Guys, come on.
结束了  比奇
It's over, Pitch.
你已经无处可藏了
There's no place to hide.
杰克 小心
Jack, look out!
是睡神
The Sandman!
伙计  久违了  见到你真高兴
Mate, you are a sight for sore eyes.
漂亮
Pretty!
你的本质
Your center?
是花了点时间
It took a while,
不过我还是弄明白了
but I figured it out.
淘气榜上  你们全都有名
You're all on naughty list!
复活节兔  跑快点
Bunny, think fast!
不
No.
你们在我面前怎么敢这么开心
You dare have fun in my presence?
我是黑暗梦魇  你们都应该怕我
I am the Boogeyman and you will fear me!
不 不
No! No.
这么快就不玩啦
Leaving the party so soon?
你都没说再见
You didn't even say goodbye.
25美分
A quarter?
这一拳是为我的小牙仙
And that's for my fairies.
你们没法摆脱我 我还会再来的
You can't get rid of me! Not forever.
恐惧永远无法真正消除
There will always be fear.
那又怎么样 只要还有一个孩子相信
So what? As long as one child believes,
我们就会和恐惧抗争到底
we will be here to fight fear.
真的吗 那它们怎么还会出现
Really? Then what are they doing here?
至少它们不是我的噩梦
They can't be my Nightmares. I'm not afraid.
看起来它们好像是被你的恐惧吸引而来的
Looks like it's your fear they smell.
不 不要啊
No, no, no. No!
不
No!
你现在准备好了吗  杰克
Are you ready now, Jack?
正式成为一名守护者
To make it official.
是你宣誓的时候了
Then is time you take Oath.
冰霜侠杰克  你是否
Will you, Jack Frost,
愿意宣誓  成为一名守护者
vow to watch over the children of the world,
用生命守卫全世界孩子们的
to guard them with your life,
希望  愿望和梦想
their hopes, their wishes, and their dreams,
因为他们就是我们的一切  我们的最初
for they are all that we have, all that we are,
我们的本质
and all that we will ever be?
我愿意
I will.
恭喜你  冰霜侠杰克 你正式成为
Then, congratulations, Jack Frost, for you are now,
也将永远是
and forevermore,
一名守护者
a Guardian.
这才像样嘛
That's my boy.
矜持点  姑娘们
Keep it together, girls.
看啊
You guys, look!
-是圣诞老人的雪橇  -那是真的
- That's Santa's sleigh. - It's real!
你们看到了吗
You guys see that?
人人都爱雪橇
Everyone loves the sleigh.
快看啊
Look at that!
该走了
Time to go.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
复活节快乐  小家伙
Happy Easter, you little ankle-biter.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
再见  复活节兔
Bye-bye, Bunny.
你要走了吗
You're leaving?
要是比奇回来了怎么办
But what if Pitch comes back?
要是我们不再相信你们了呢
What if we stop believing again?
要是我看不见你了呢
If I can't see you...
慢一点  慢一点
Slow down, slow down.
要是太阳出来了
You're telling me you stop
你就不相信月亮了吗
believing in the moon when the sun comes up?
不会
No.
如果云遮住太阳
Okay. Do you stop believing in the sun
你就不相信太阳了吗
when clouds block it out?
不会
No.
我们一直都在  杰米  现在
We'll always be there, Jamie. And now,
我们还会一直在你心里
we'll always be here.
说起来你也算是个守护者呢
Which kind of makes you a Guardian, too.
杰克
Jack!
我叫冰霜侠杰克
My name is Jack Frost.
我是个守护者
And I'm a Guardian.
我是怎么知道的呢
How do I know that?
是月亮告诉我的
Because the moon told me so.
当月亮告诉你某些事情时
So when the moon tells you something,
要相信它
believe it.